<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Kings Majesties speciall direction concerning the finishing of the fortifications, in and about the city of Oxford</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B19203</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">19729512</idno>
  <idno type="VID">205624</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240856989</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C2773</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">19729512</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B19203)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 205624)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1697:39)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Kings Majesties speciall direction concerning the finishing of the fortifications, in and about the city of Oxford</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Leonard Lichfield ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Oxford :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1643</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>At head of title: Charles R.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1642-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:205624:1"/>
            <head>CHARLES R. The <hi>Kings Majesties</hi> speciall direction concerning the finishing of the <hi>Fortifications,</hi> in and about the City of <hi>OXFORD.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>IS Majestie finding that the Fortifications in and about this City of <hi>Oxford,</hi> which are necessary for the defence and preservation thereof upon all suddain occasions, for the safety of the University and City, and of all those who are, or shall be therein, have long been in hand, and are not yet fully finished, but would in a short time be perfected, were those Works effectually followed, and would with much lesse charg and trouble to Him and to His Maiesties Subjects of this County, if the same were rightly ordered; Doth therefore require and straitly charg that the Work of the Fortifications be from hence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forth performed, untill they shall be fully finished, in this manner following.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>First,</hi> that by the advice of the <hi>Governour</hi> of the Towne, the <hi>Vice-Chancellour</hi> of the University, and the <hi>Major</hi> of the City, the names of all the men who are Inhabitants, or Residents either in the University, or City, or Suburbs thereof, being above the age of Sixteen, and under the age of Sixty, be, as exactly as they can, taken into a Roll of paper, and the se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verall Parishes and places, where they dwell, be expressed in that Roll with all the speed they can.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> That the generall Roll being thus made up, they be divided into six severall parts, by the advice aforesaid, and the same being so divided every sixth part be set into a severall Roll.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly,</hi> That every sixth part be appointed to attend the Works of the Fortifications, one day in every week, untill the whole Work be fully finished at such place or places, and in such manner as Colonell <hi>Lloyd</hi> shall appoint, who hath the care of the Fortifications.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fourthly,</hi> That they shall in every week begin at six of the clock in the morning, and continue untill eleven before noone, and again from one in the afternoone untill six of the clock towards night, and follow the same diligently and sedulously.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fifthly,</hi> That an houre before six in the morning, the <hi>Governour</hi> shall appoint one Drummer to call the workmen to their work, and so to continue at the Works till eleven before noone; and a Drummer to do the like at one of the clock in the afternoone, and continue untill six at night to encourage the workers at the Work.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Sixthly,</hi> That those Gentlemen who have specially been desired to take care of the Fortifications, shall three of them at the least, by consent among themselves, every day see the workers called upon, &amp; observe who are negligent, and who are not, and call over the Rolls every day by themselves, or whom they will appoint, and observe who are absent, and every one who neglect their turne to be noted upon the Roll every day, and every half day before noone, and afternoone, as is before directed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Seventhly,</hi> That every Person who shall not personally work in his turne, in such manner as aforesaid, shall pay twelve pence for every whole day, or six pence for every half day, into the hands of such Treasurer, or Treasurers, as the Gentlemen imployed for His Majesties service, as aforesaid shall appoint, for that purpose, to be disposed of, as these Gentlemen shall appoint by His Majesties direction.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Eightly,</hi> That the Gentlemen before mentioned conferre with the <hi>Governour, Sheriffe</hi> of the County, and <hi>Major</hi> of the Citty, that Spades, Shovells, Mattocks, Hand-barrowes, Wheele-barrowes, and all other tooles necessary for the Work be provided, and delivered to them who are to use them, and delivered again safely to the owners, when the Work shall be done.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Ninthly,</hi> That if any shall be found to neglect either to perform the work, or pay the monyes in such sort as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, the Gentlemen trusted, as aforesaid, shall certifie the <hi>Governour</hi> of the Defaulters, that they may be proceeded against as Persons disaffected to His Majesties Service.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Tenthly,</hi> That, if any Seruant do neglect to work in his turne, the Master, Mistres, or Dame, shall pay for such Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant, in such proportion as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Commissioners are lastly desired to call upon the</hi> Defaulters, <hi>for the time past, to send for the</hi> Sheriffe <hi>to see in what state that accompt stands, and to cause it to be put in full execution.</hi> June the eight, 1643.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at Oxford by LEONARD LICHFIELD, Printer to the University. 1643.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>